<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Kelly Heard</title>
 <link href="https://kellyheard.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://kellyheard.com//"/>
 <updated>2017-05-25T15:29:16+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://kellyheard.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kelly Heard</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>A Simple Plugin Example</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/sitecore-commerce-plugin-sample"/>
   <updated>2017-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/sitecore-commerce-plugin-sample</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;tldrTitle&quot;&gt;tldr&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I made a simple plugin for Sitecore Commerce 8.2.1. The source code is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heardk/commerce-plugins/tree/master/Commerce.Plugin.Shared.Cart&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of Sitecore Commerce was released back in January, with version 8.2.1. An update to that release is expected soon, but I thought I’d discuss some of the new capability around the plugin architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make the process of adding your own custom business logic as easy as possible. Obviously, this is something that a developer is often required to do in an implementation. No solution is perfect out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, the entire Commerce engine is based on plugins so a customer can chose which modules they require for their implementation. It’s called &lt;em&gt;opt-in complexity&lt;/em&gt; and provides quite a bit more deployment flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.sitecore.net/Downloads/Sitecore_Commerce/821/Sitecore_Commerce_821.aspx&quot;&gt;Release Package&lt;/a&gt;, an SDK is also provided which contains a &lt;em&gt;customer sample solution&lt;/em&gt;. The solution contains a couple of existing plugins, and a Visual Studio project template for building your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shared-cart-plugin&quot;&gt;Shared Cart Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a simple plugin, just to show how it’s done. The requirement is to be able to share a shopping cart across multiple sites, but the CSR and fulfillment process needs to know what store the product was purchased from. Here’s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the product is added to the basket, I check the current context and add the current shop name to the new component:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c#&quot; data-lang=&quot;c#&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//Get shopname from context
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shopname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CommerceContext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetObjects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Shop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;FirstOrDefault&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//Add component to CartlineComponent
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SharedCartLineComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ShopName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shopname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I need to display this value in the Customer &amp;amp; Orders Manager when a CSR looks at the line item details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c#&quot; data-lang=&quot;c#&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;HasComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SharedCartLineComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sharedCartLineComponent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SharedCartLineComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//Add shop name property to the line item view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lineEntityView&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ViewProperty&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ShopName&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DisplayName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Store&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IsReadOnly&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;RawValue&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sharedCartLineComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ShopName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out the full code example on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heardk/commerce-plugins/tree/master/Commerce.Plugin.Shared.Cart&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, specifically &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ConfigureSitecore.cs&lt;/code&gt;. This is where your plugin functionality gets injected into the Commerce Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation on plugins is a work in progres, but in the meantime, the samples in the SDK (and this one) will definitely give you an idea of how it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cross posted on my Sitecore Blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.sitecore.net/technical_blogs/b/the_commerce_experience&quot;&gt;The Commerce Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Every Song Considered</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/every-song-considered"/>
   <updated>2017-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/every-song-considered</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;tldrTitle&quot;&gt;tldr&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I released a small side project called Every Song Considered. Listen to 30-second previews of songs from All Songs Considered. Visit here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://everysong.rocks/&quot;&gt;http://everysong.rocks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally released a little side project. I’ve started so many but just never finished any of them. Either I lost interest, or something changed along the way that made me rethink the idea altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;npr&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/&quot;&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic podcast by the good folks at NPR. I’m a big fan of Bob and Robin and the music they (and others) share on the show. It introduces me to a lot of the music I end up listening to. The show’s blog posts on the NPR site don’t always include music, so I wanted a way to bring all the shows together that contained song lists and provide a consistent way to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/api/index&quot;&gt;NPR API&lt;/a&gt; I was able to easily get a list of the shows and the attributes that go along with each. Apart from having to deal with inconsistencies in the data, a complete list of &lt;em&gt;All Songs&lt;/em&gt; shows containing song lists was relatively straightforward to get. The next step was to display the list of songs, with artist and album information and a small image of the album cover. Previewing the song was tricky as this data wasn’t always avaialble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spotify-to-the-rescue&quot;&gt;Spotify to the rescue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their extensive set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.spotify.com/web-api/&quot;&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to get the song preview I was looking for. It would have been great to play the entire song, but for now the preview would do. There was a problem though. There was no common unique identifier between what I was getting from NPR and what I needed to get accurate data from Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPC was my first try, but for some reason, they both use different UPCs to identify albums. I had to resort to searching against the Spotify API with artist, album and song information. In most cases, this method returns accurate results but there are edge cases where it might not. I haven’t seen this behaviour yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-resulting-mvp&quot;&gt;The Resulting MVP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/2017-03-21_1617.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly not going to win any design awards, but does what it’s supposed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in the process of building some new functionality that will allow you to create Spotify playlists based on selected songs.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ecommerce Trends - No. 3</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-trends-three"/>
   <updated>2017-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-trends-three</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The state of mobile web isn’t what it should be and I like that others are pointing out this lack of usability. There are two such articles below, essentially warning us that we need to focus more on making these experiences better for customers. After all, the number of people using mobile browsers is only going to increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;auto-detect-city-and-state-inputs-based-on-the-users-postal-codehttpsbaymardcomblogzip-code-auto-detection-baymard-institute&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baymard.com/blog/zip-code-auto-detection&quot;&gt;Auto-Detect ‘City’ and ‘State’ Inputs Based on the User’s Postal Code&lt;/a&gt; (Baymard Institute)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still many sites that could vastly improve their mobile experience. One such example, is reducing the complexity of the checkout process. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://baymard.com/blog/checkout-flow-average-form-fields&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, there are twice as many form fields as necessary. One suggestion in this article that I really like is to auto-fill the state and province fields based on the zip or postal code entered by the user. Even with the fields out of their traditional order (zip code first) users found that to be a great way to save time and reduce the complexity of the checkout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-overcome-shopper-hesitations-to-buying-gifts-onlinehttpswwwinternetretailercomcommentary20161202how-overcome-shopper-hesitations-buying-gifts-online-internet-retailer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetretailer.com/commentary/2016/12/02/how-overcome-shopper-hesitations-buying-gifts-online&quot;&gt;How to overcome shopper hesitations to buying gifts online&lt;/a&gt; (Internet Retailer)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready for another new technology term? Gift Commerce or G-Commerce is used to describe the process of buying a product as a gift for someone else. Gift card sales are very strong, but some just don’t like the impersonal nature of buying someone a gift card. The article is about offering new features (and products) that cater to the gift buyer, like a gift guide, gift suggestions and gift wrapping. But it’s hard to buy a gift for someone when you need to know a size, favourite colour or even the correct shipping address in some cases. The answer? Get them to pick for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways-from-nrfs-big-show-2017httpwwwretaildivecomnews4-takeaways-from-nrfs-big-show-2017434218-retail-dive&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.retaildive.com/news/4-takeaways-from-nrfs-big-show-2017/434218/&quot;&gt;4 takeaways from NRF’s Big Show 2017&lt;/a&gt; (Retail Dive)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than 3 full days of standing, having interesting conversations with customers and booth swag, there were some interesting takeaways from the show. Retail Dive highlights these, but definitely two that top my list are more effort around omnichannel scenarios and thinking more like a digital native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-mobile-website-suckshttpblogsforrestercomtedschadler17-01-22-yourmobilewebsitesucks-forrester&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.forrester.com/ted_schadler/17-01-22-your_mobile_website_sucks&quot;&gt;Your Mobile Website Sucks&lt;/a&gt; (Forrester)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This a great part 2 to the first in the series, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.forrester.com/ted_schadler/16-10-05-drunk_history_of_your_mobile_strategy&quot;&gt;A Drunk History of your Mobile Strategy&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, you have to access the research to really dig into the details, but these posts are a good start. A mobile strategy is not simply making your desktop site responsive, but addressing what exactly a customer is looking for when they browse your site from a phone or tablet. By 2019, 59% of web traffic will be mobile so it’s time to take a different approach to mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successful-e-commerce-companies-that-made-it-big-with-content-marketinghttpwwwinccomsujan-patel7-successful-e-commerce-companies-that-made-it-big-with-content-marketinghtml-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/sujan-patel/7-successful-e-commerce-companies-that-made-it-big-with-content-marketing.html&quot;&gt;7 Successful E-Commerce Companies That Made It Big With Content Marketing&lt;/a&gt; (Inc.)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content marketing on your e-commerce site can drive addtional revenue, increase brand loyalty and also promote brand awareness. A couple of brands in this article have some great ideas on how to accomplish this. My favourite is Beardbrand, fostering a community of users around the idea of &lt;em&gt;urban beardsmen&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ecommerce Trends - No. 2</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-links-two"/>
   <updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-links-two</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The second series of ecommerce links discusses interactive email, products-as-a-service and a few posts on user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-be-the-year-of-interactive-emailhttpsmediumdave-baileycom2017-is-the-year-of-interactive-email-b6c1c4960c72za9xrq7uy-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.dave-bailey.com/2017-is-the-year-of-interactive-email-b6c1c4960c72#.za9xrq7uy&quot;&gt;2017 Will Be The Year Of Interactive Email&lt;/a&gt; (Medium)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app market is over saturated and fewer people are downloading new apps. Email has the opportunity to become the next big thing for developers. Content creators get more engagement out of their email newsletters than other methods. The article discusses an example of an interactive shopping cart, that allows users to make changes to their basket and even view product details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-as-service-a-necessary-evolutionhttpwwwthe-future-of-commercecom20161107product-as-service-future-of-ecommerce&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.the-future-of-commerce.com/2016/11/07/product-as-service/&quot;&gt;Product-as-service: A necessary evolution&lt;/a&gt; (Future of Ecommerce)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are expecting more value from a product they purchase. Manufacturers or vendors need to evolve to offering an integrated product and service offering. “Manufacturers transition from selling physical products to selling the business outcomes the products will deliver.” (from an additional &lt;a href=&quot;https://idc-community.com/manufacturing/manufacturing-value-chain/the_rise_of_product_as_a_service_in_manufacturing_and_some_of_the_te&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-top-four-e-commerce-elements-to-ab-testhttpswwwinternetretailercomcommentary20161020top-four-e-commerce-elements-b-test-internet-retailer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetretailer.com/commentary/2016/10/20/top-four-e-commerce-elements-b-test&quot;&gt;The top four e-commerce elements to A/B test&lt;/a&gt; (Internet Retailer)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, why would you guess at what your customers like if you could find out for certain? Test pricing, because a lower price may not actually sell more products. Is it Add to Cart or Buy Now? The wording and UI experience make a difference in whether or not the customer takes that final step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;crucial--but-overlooked--aspects-of-mobile-ecommerce-uxhttpbloglemonstandcommobile-ecommerce-best-practices-lemonstand&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lemonstand.com/mobile-ecommerce-best-practices/&quot;&gt;9 Crucial – But Overlooked – Aspects of Mobile eCommerce UX&lt;/a&gt; (Lemonstand)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on a Baymard Institute mobile usability study, it was found that many sites don’t honour some of the standard mobile features on their mobile-enabled webites. One of the most obvious for me is the ability to take advantage of the proper mobile keyboard (based on the field you’re in) and disabling auto-correct during the checkout process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-layout-bugs-keep-haunting-e-commerce-siteshttpbaymardcomblogecommerce-layout-bugs-baymard-institute&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://baymard.com/blog/ecommerce-layout-bugs&quot;&gt;How Layout Bugs Keep Haunting E-Commerce Sites&lt;/a&gt; (Baymard Institute)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even some of the biggest names in ecommerce are haunted by layout bugs, either in a traditional desktop browser or on a mobile device. They don’t purposely deploy sites with these bugs, but just that they have a harder time identifying them. Server crashes are easily logged and monitored, while layout bugs are not as easily surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ecommerce Trends - No. 1</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-links-one"/>
   <updated>2016-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/ecommerce-links-one</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some recent articles and blog posts on all things ecommerce and retail. You’ll notice I named it “one”. I’m hoping to follow that up with a “two” and “three” and so on. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-science-of-smell-how-retailers-can-use-scent-marketing-to-influence-shoppershttpcompany-retailmyshopifycomblogsblogthe-science-of-smell-how-retailers-can-use-scent-marketing-to-make-more-sales-shopify&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://company-retail.myshopify.com/blogs/blog/the-science-of-smell-how-retailers-can-use-scent-marketing-to-make-more-sales&quot;&gt;The Science of Smell: How Retailers Can Use Scent Marketing to Influence Shoppers&lt;/a&gt; (Shopify)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all walked into a mall and known instantly if there was an Abercrombie located somewhere inside. Many retailers use scent to help market their brand and improve conversion rates. Even smaller retailers can take advantage of Scent Marketing to improve in store experiences and keep customers there longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;report-social-commerce-on-the-rise-despite-sluggish-business-readinesshttpwwwcmocomauarticle607234report-social-commerce-rise-despite-sluggish-business-readiness-cmo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cmo.com.au/article/607234/report-social-commerce-rise-despite-sluggish-business-readiness/&quot;&gt;Report: Social commerce on the rise despite sluggish business readiness&lt;/a&gt; (CMO)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from a small percentage of standout ecommerce purchasing experiences, most are not what I would consider worthy given the number of technology platforms that make this possible. This report identifies some interesting figures: “&lt;em&gt;..71 per cent use their mobile devices to make payments, yet only 49 per cent of businesses are mobile optimised. Almost one-third (31 per cent) of businesses stated they have no plans to optimise for mobile sales..&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-behavioural-economics-and-dynamic-pricing-with-your-productshttpwwwmindtheproductcom201610using-behavioural-economics-dynamic-pricing-products-mind-the-product&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtheproduct.com/2016/10/using-behavioural-economics-dynamic-pricing-products/&quot;&gt;Using Behavioural Economics and Dynamic Pricing With Your Products&lt;/a&gt; (Mind the Product)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often find myself falling for at least a couple of these pricing strategies; scarcity and value relativity come to mind. Watch the video and learn more about behavioural economics and how it can be used to influence customer buying behaviours. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtheproduct.com/2016/10/using-behavioural-economics-dynamic-pricing-products/&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-22-most-innovative-web-platforms-of-2016httpswwwfastcodesigncom3064301innovation-by-designthe-22-most-innovative-web-platforms-of-2016-fast-company-design&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcodesign.com/3064301/innovation-by-design/the-22-most-innovative-web-platforms-of-2016&quot;&gt;The 22 Most Innovative Web Platforms Of 2016&lt;/a&gt; (Fast Company Design)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who doesn’t love a list of top &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;. This list takes us through some really great web platforms and applications, some I recognize but a few were new to me. My favourites: Avametric, SAP Build and Watson News Explorer. Check out the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-why-68-of-users-abandon-their-carthttpbaymardcomblogecommerce-checkout-usability-report-and-benchmark-baymard-institute&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://baymard.com/blog/ecommerce-checkout-usability-report-and-benchmark&quot;&gt;Research: Why 68% of Users Abandon Their Cart&lt;/a&gt; (Baymard Institute)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retailers are always looking for ways to lower cart abandonment. Most would assume (incorrectly) that to do this requires a lot of development and redesign. According to the research, we can increase conversions by doing smaller page layout changes to make the process of buying simpler for the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://baymard.com/checkout-usability/benchmark/step-type&quot;&gt;Checkout Step Types&lt;/a&gt; - navigate 50 ecommerce sites checkout processes to see what they get right and what they get wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sitecore Commerce 8.2 - What's New</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/new-sitecore-commerce-82"/>
   <updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/new-sitecore-commerce-82</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The release of Sitecore Commerce 8.2 marked another milestone in the continued development and improvement of our Commerce product. While there are great things planned for 8.3 and beyond, there are some significant improvements and new features that we can take advantage of now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full release notes are &lt;a href=&quot;http://commercesdn.sitecore.net/SCpbCS82/releasenotes/en-us/index.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but let me walk you through some of what I think are the most exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support-for-azure-web-apps&quot;&gt;Support for Azure Web Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 8.1, we were given new tools, in the form of PowerShell CmdLets, that make installing and configuring Commerce Server much easier. With that, came further support for Azure and the Sitecore Azure Module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long, farewell PuP, it’s been nice knowing you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 8.2 release, we see added support for Azure Web Apps using registry-free COM and Commerce Server specific NuGet packages. Now you can deploy to the cloud without needing to install Commerce Server. There are some caveats though, like not being able to use Catalog Import/Export because of the COM+ requirement, so be sure to look at the release notes for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information on Azure Web Apps deployments for Sitecore Commerce can be found in the documentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://commercesdn.sitecore.net/SCpbCS82/SitecoreCommerceDeploymentGuide/en-us/index.html#c_BuidingAzurePaaSDeployment.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;custom-catalog-fields&quot;&gt;Custom Catalog Fields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating the initial catalog schema, a decision needs to be made about where a particular field should be stored. Product data needed for the completed transaction is best stored in the Catalog. If the attribute is simply to enrich the way the product looks on the site, like images, videos or content, simply create the field in Sitecore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of these product enrichment fields are attached to a product in the catalog using a field called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/02/custom-product-attributes-and-the-externalsettings-field.aspx&quot;&gt;External Settings&lt;/a&gt;. The problem is if an external system provides updates to the catalog (like through the Catalog Web Service from an ERP or PIM) the external settings field could be lost, and with it, any fields you added to the data template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the launch of 8.2, you can now specify if you want to store these External Settings with the original product or in a separate product catalog. Now if a catalog is updated from a legacy system or through some kind of import, the External Settings field won’t be overwritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Documentation is still being updated. I’ll provide details on how to do this soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commerce-reports&quot;&gt;Commerce Reports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 8.1, Commerce reporting was added to the Experience Profile with a focus on individual contacts. With the launch of 8.2, we see a number of new reports and charts added to Experience Analytics, providing a view of commerce data as it applies to all contacts and interactions.  A full list of these reports are available in the release notes, but here are the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Selling Products and Most Viewed Categories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/82-reports-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shopping Cart Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/82-reports-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;More&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also point out that we’ve begun to restructure our Commerce documentation. All docs related to Commerce can now be found in one convenient place, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.sitecore.net/sitecore_commerce&quot;&gt;doc.sitecore.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more enhancements and bug fixes. We’ll be talking more about them in the weeks to come, as we dive deeper into some of the new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.sitecore.net/technical_blogs/b/the_commerce_experience/posts/what-39-s-new-in-sitecore-commerce-8-2&quot;&gt;community.sitecore.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sitecore Commerce Demo Source</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/commerce-demo-source"/>
   <updated>2015-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/commerce-demo-source</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my Sitecore blog, The Commerce Experience, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/10/commerce-demo-for-partners.aspx&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; the release of the source code for our Sitecore Commerce Demo. Check it out for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/10/commerce-demo-for-partners.aspx&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Custom Product Relationships in Sitecore Commerce</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/custom-product-relationships"/>
   <updated>2015-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/custom-product-relationships</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my Sitecore blog, The Commerce Experience, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/08/custom-product-relationships-in-sitecore-commerce.aspx&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; creating custom product relationships to improve merchandiser experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/08/custom-product-relationships-in-sitecore-commerce.aspx&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Custom Product Attributes in the External Setttings Field</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/custom-product-attributes"/>
   <updated>2015-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/custom-product-attributes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my Sitecore blog, The Commerce Experience, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/02/custom-product-attributes-and-the-externalsettings-field.aspx&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; customizing product schemas with Sitecore Commerce pb Commerce Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecore.net/learn/blogs/technical-blogs/kelly-heard/posts/2015/02/custom-product-attributes-and-the-externalsettings-field.aspx&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Last Minute Trip to SFO</title>
   <link href="https://kellyheard.com//blog/last-minute-trip-sfo"/>
   <updated>2015-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://kellyheard.com//blog/last-minute-trip-sfo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took a recent trip to San Francisco, following my wife as she was attending a conference. I’ve been there before, but took the time to get out and take some pictures of landmarks I hadn’t had time to photograph last time. Photographs of the Golden Gate bridge are not new, but I wanted one of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a good part of one day at Baker Beach trying to get the shot you see here. And as you can also see, the weather wasn’t exactly the greatest, but still turned out to be a half-way decent shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the whole album on Flickr, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/greensuitcase/albums/72157654661669251&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
